Contact

New Delhi 9871379513 (Mobile) bharatlamba33@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/bharat-lamba-22478633 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Loans

Team Management
Business Development

Languages

Hindi

Punjabi

English

Bharat Lamba

Associate Vice President - Administration and Infrastructure (North & East Zone) at Poonawalla Fincorp Ltd. Delhi

Summary

A competent professional with over 27 years of experience business development, profit centre operations, recovery management in the financial services sector. Currently associated with Poonawala Fin-Corp (Formerly Magma Fincorp Ltd.) Ltd as Zonal Head-corporate services. A proactive leader and planner with expertise in strategic planning, market plan execution account management, pre-sales efforts with skills in staffing, management reorganization and targeted marketing. Demonstrated skills in team supervision and relationship management as well as exceptional communication abilities to cut across the organizational levels and accomplish targets.

Specialties: 1. Profit Centre Operations

Conducting competitor analysis by keeping a breast of market trends and competitor moves to achieve market share metrics.

2. Business Development

Driving sales initiatives achieving business goals & managing the frontline sales team .

3. Channel /Team Management

Effective leadership developing channel partners for achieving business volumes consistently and profitably and motivating team for max productivity

Experience

Poonawalla Fincorp 27 years

AVP -Zonal Head - Corporate Services September 1995 - Present (27 years) New Delhi, Delhi, India

- Showed excellent leadership for the overall administrative corporate services for the North Zone Branches by initiating various projects, work out budgets

and expansion plans for multiple departments (Housing Finance, Asset Business, Loan etc.) within the company.

- Met compliance and administrative demands of more than 70 offices in North India along with Facilities and Security for the Employees. Lead and motivated team from both internal and external stakeholder organisations
- Substantive contribution in cost control of up to 1 million dollars (by rental reductions during the lockdown period) and thus supporting business to increase the profitability.
- Brought laurels to the organization by regularly meeting the CSR goals of the company every year and promoted the companies in more than 50 press release.

ZSM-SME Loans

September 2007 - August 2012 (5 years)

Established the SME products in North From Zero and took it to level of 10 cr business per month and established stable sales team for successfull deliveries.

Regional Manager - CV and Car Loans 2000 - 2007 (7 years)

Handled Car and LCV product developed these products and given cent percent Results with quality portfolio.

Education

Delhi University

Graduate · (1989 - 1991)

Master of Business Administration - MBA · (2008 - 2010) Sikkim Manipal University of Health, Medical and Technological Sciences

D61976bil1986hool